A Guide to the David Rockefeller Personal and Professional papers, RG 1 and RG 2 FA436
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller, 1918-1981; 1945-1961; 2; 19.37 Cubic Feet 51 letter document boxes
  - Personal correspondence, 1939-1961
    - Fl-Ford, 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 288)
    - Ford-Frenkel, 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 289)
    - Franklin, Mr. and Mrs. George (Benjy) Jr., 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 290)
    - Franklin, Mr. and Mrs. George (Benjy) Jr., 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 290a)
    - Fri-Fun, 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 291)
    - Gab-Gan, 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 292)
    - Gar-Gas, 1939-1961 (Box 26, Folder 293)
    - Gat-Gau, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 294)
    - Gax-Gil, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 295)
    - Gim-Goz, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 296)
    - Grace, J. Peter, Jr., 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 297)
    - Grae-Grun, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 298)
    - Gu-Gw, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 299)
    - Gu-Gw, 1939-1961 (Box 27, Folder 299a)
    - Haa-Hal, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 300)
    - Haa-Hal, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 300a)
    - Ham-Han, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 301)
    - Hara-Harp, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 302)
    - Harr-Harv, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 303)
    - Has-Hei, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 304)
    - Hel-Hi, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 305)
    - Hoa-Hol, 1939-1961 (Box 28, Folder 306)
    - Hom-Hos, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 307)
    - Hou-Hy, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 308)
    - Hou-Hy, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 308a)
    - Ib-Ina, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 309)
    - Ing-Iv, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 310)
    - Ja, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 311)
    - Je, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 312)
    - Je, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 312a)
    - Jo-Ju, 1939-1961 (Box 29, Folder 313)
    - Ka-Kei, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 314)
    - Ka-Kei, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 314a)
    - Kel-Kh, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 315)
    - Kimpton, Lawrence, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 316)
    - Kid-Kin, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 317)
    - Kir-Kn, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 318)
    - Ko-Kra, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 319)
    - Kre-Ky, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 320)
    - Lab-Lap, 1939-1961 (Box 30, Folder 321)
    - Lar-Laz, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    - Lea-Lew, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 323)
    - Lia-Lin, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 324)
    - Lip-Lon, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 325)
    - Lip-Lon, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 325a)
    - Loo-Ly, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 326)
    - Mac-Maj, 1939-1961 (Box 31, Folder 327)
    - Mal-Mar, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 328)
    - Marshall, George C., 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 329)
    - Mas-Mb, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 330)
    - McA-McF, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 331)
    - McA-McF, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 331a)
    - McGrath, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 332)
    - McGrath, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 332a)
    - McG-McN, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 333)
    - Me, 1939-1961 (Box 32, Folder 334)
    - Mic-Miller, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 335)
    - Milliken-Mitchell, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 336)
    - Model-Montague, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 337)
    - Montenecourt-Monod, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 338)
    - Moore-Morton, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 339)
    - Moses, Robert, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 340)
    - Mos-Mow, 1939-1961 (Box 33, Folder 341)
    - Mu-My, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 342)
    - Na-Nev, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 344)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 345)
    - New-Ni, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 346)
    - Nicholson, Commander V.E.B., 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 347)
    - Nk-Ny, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 348)
    - Oa-Od, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 349)
    - Og-Ow, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 350)
    - Og-Ow, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 350a)
    - Pac-Pal, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 351)
    - Packard, Arthur W., 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 352)
    - Pan-Pav, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 353)
    - Percy, Charles H., 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 354)
    - Pe, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 355)
    - Pf-Ph, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 356)
    - Pi-Pl, 1939-1961 (Box 35, Folder 357)
    - Poc-Poo, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 358)
    - Pop-Pow, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 359)
    - Pr, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 360)
    - Pu-Py, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 361)
    - Q, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 362)
    - Ra, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 363)
    - Rea-Reg, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 364)
    - Rei-Rey, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 365)
    - Rh-Ri, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 366)
    - Rob, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 367)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette H., 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 368)
    - Rockefeller, Helen (Mrs. Godfrey S.), 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 369)
    - Rockefeller, Martha Baird, 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 372)
    - Rockefeller, Mary Clark (Tod), 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 373)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 375)
    - Rockefeller, Rodman C., 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 376)
    - Rockefeller, J. Stillman, 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 378)
    - Rockefeller, William A., 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 379)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1942-1948 (Box 37, Folder 380)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1949-1953 (Box 37, Folder 381)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1954-1958 (Box 37, Folder 382)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 383)
    - Condolences on the death of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller: Name Illegible, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 384)
    - Condolences on the death of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller: Not in Card Catalog, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 385)
    - Condolences on the death of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller: Includd n Card Catalog, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 386)
    - Rockefeller Center Luncheon Club, 1939-1961 (Box 37, Folder 387)
    - Rog-Ros, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 388)
    - Rou-Rug, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 389)
    - Rum-Ry, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 390)
    - Saa-Sas, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 391)
    - Sau-Sche, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 392)
    - Schi-Scu, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 393)
    - Se, 1939-1961 (Box 38, Folder 394)
    - Sh, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 395)
    - Si-Sl, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 396)
    - Si-Sl, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 396a)
    - Sm, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 397)
    - Smith, General Ralph C., 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 398)
    - Sn-Sp, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 399)
    - Sn-Sp, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 399a)
      Restriction-Hope Rockefeller
    - Sproul, Dr. Robert Gordon, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 400)
    - Sta-Ste, 1939-1961 (Box 39, Folder 400)
    - Sti-Sto, 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 402)
    - Str-Stu, 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 403)
    - Stuart and Turner Ltd., 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 404)
    - Su, 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 405)
    - Sw-Sy, 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 406)
    - Ta-Te, 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 407)
    - Teves, Ernst A., 1939-1961 (Box 40, Folder 408)
    - Th, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 409)
    - Ti-Tr, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 410)
    - Ts-Ty, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 411)
    - U, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 412)
    - Va, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 413)
    - Ve-Vo, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 414)
    - Wa, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 415)
    - Was-Wau, 1939-1961 (Box 41, Folder 416)
    - Wea-Wei, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 417)
    - Wel-Wes, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 418)
    - Wh, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 419)
    - Wic-Willcox, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 420)
    - Williams, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 421)
    - Willems-Witman, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 422)
    - Willems-Witman, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 422a)
    - Wo, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 423)
    - Wr-Wy, 1939-1961 (Box 42, Folder 424)
    - Ya-Ye, 1939-1961 (Box 43, Folder 425)
    - Yo-Yu, 1939-1961 (Box 43, Folder 426)
    - Z, 1939-1961 (Box 43, Folder 427)
    - Unsorted miscellaneous correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 43, Folder 428)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1925-1928 (Box 44, Folder 434)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1929 (Box 44, Folder 435)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1930-1931 (Box 44, Folder 436)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1930-1931 (Box 44, Folder 436a)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1932 (Box 44, Folder 437)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 438)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1934 January-1934 June (Box 44, Folder 439)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1934 July-1934 December (Box 44, Folder 440)
    - David Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 441)
  - Philanthropic contribution summaries, 1948-1952 (Box 43, Folder 429)
  - Philanthropic contribution summaries, 1953-1959 (Box 43, Folder 430)
  - Philanthropic annual contribution reports
    - 1940-1945 (Box 43, Folder 431)
    - 1948-1952 (Box 43, Folder 432)
    - 1953-1960 (Box 43, Folder 433)
    - 1953-1960 (Box 43, Folder 433a)
  - Park Avenue Baptist Church: Sunday School Student Scrapbook, 1925-1926 (Box 44, Folder 442)
  - International Executive Service Corps, 1964-1966
    Biographical/Historical note
    IESC was a private, nonprofit organization directed and managed by members of the business community. Its primary objective was to help improve the performance of privately owned industrial and commerical enterprises in developing countries in the fields of general management, production, marketing, and financial control. While the organization recognized that help was needed also in noncommercial fields such as education, public welfare, and professional activities, this was not within the planned scope of IESC.
    IESC made available on request experienced executives for limited periods of time--usually three to six months--to advise management of enterprises seeking assistance and to help implement the recommendations made. IESC dealt directly with individual businesses and not through the governments of the United States and the host country. David Rockefeller served a the first chair of the board of IESC.
    - Promotional and press materials, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 443)
    - Memos, policies, and procedures, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 444)
    - Program review, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 445)
    - Reports and debriefings, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 446)
    - Individual information sheets, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 447)
    - Project data sheets, 1964-1965 (Box 45, Folder 448)
    - Project data materials: #1-#15, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 449)
    - Project data materials: #16-#27, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 450)
    - Project data materials: #42-#59, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 451)
    - Project data materials: #60-#83, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 452)
    - Project status summary, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 453)
    - Project biographies, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 454)
    - Project status for Central America, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 455)
    - Project status for South America, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 456)
    - Project status for Middle East, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 457)
    - Project status for Far East, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 458)
    - Project status for Central America, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 459)
    - Project status for South America, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 460)
    - Project status for Middle East, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 461)
    - Project status for Far East, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 462)
  - Files from office at Chase Manhattan Bank
    - Luncheon for Presient Diem of Viet Nam, 1957 May (Box 47, Folder 463)
    - Citizens Housing and Planning Council award, 1961 May (Box 47, Folder 464)
    - Brown University's John D. Rockefeller Jr. Library dedication, 1964 November (Box 47, Folder 465)
    - Ed Koch and DR's Middle East perspective, 1969-1970 (Box 47, Folder 466)
    - Urban Coalition Task Force on Housing, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 467)
    - Harvard Commitee on University Resources, 1970-1971 (Box 47, Folder 468)
    - Transportation bond issue, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 469)
    - Republican Party kick-off dinner, 1971 March (Box 47, Folder 470)
    - Republican state committee dinner, 1971 June (Box 47, Folder 471)
    - Ripon Society contribution, 1971-1972 (Box 47, Folder 472)
    - Asia Society dinner honoring Henry Kissinger, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 473)
    - Nixon campaign ad use of DR's name, 1972 October (Box 47, Folder 474)
    - Political correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 47, Folder 475)
    - Political "no action" correspondence, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 476)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller Charitable Trust advisory committee luncheon, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 477)
    - Arkansas Arts Center announcement ceremony, 1974 February (Box 47, Folder 478)
    - Rockefeller University annunal retirement dinner, 1974 April (Box 47, Folder 479)
    - Taiwan Medical Center contribution, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 480)
    - Nelson Rockefeller's confirmation as U.S. Vice President, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 481)
    - Trips to Denmark (cancelled) and Norway, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 482)
    - Asian travels and art purchases, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 483)
    - Political correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 484)
    - Political "no action" correspondence, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 485)
    - Harvard University finance club speech, 1977 (Box 48, Folder 486)
    - Dinner in honor of Shabanou of Iran, 1977-1978 (Box 48, Folder 487)
    - Asia Society dinner, 1979 May (Box 48, Folder 488)
    - Republican Eagles luncheon, 1979 September (Box 48, Folder 489)
    - Joseph Reed's trip to Morocco, 1980-1981 (Box 48, Folder 490)
    - David and Peggy Rockefeller's 40th wedding anniversary, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 491)
    - Harvard University, 1961-1973 (Box 49, Folder 492)
    - International House, 1957-1970 (Box 49, Folder 493)
    - Morningside Heights, Inc., 1953-1974 (Box 49, Folder 494)
    - White House Fellows Commission, 1964-1965 (Box 49, Folder 495)
    - St. Bart's property, 1970-1979 (Box 49, Folder 496)
    - Clivus Multrum system, 1970-1979 (Box 49, Folder 497)
    - Clivus Multrum system, 1970-1979 (Box 49, Folder 497a)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller's election as governor, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 498)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller's presidential campaign, 1968 May-July (Box 49, Folder 499)
    - Rockefeller for President: state lists for DR to contact, 1968 May (Box 49, Folder 500)
    - Rockefeller for President: delegates by state, 1968 July (Box 49, Folder 501)
    - Rockefeller for President: finance committee, 1968 July (Box 49, Folder 502)
  - Condolences on the death of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1960
    - A-B, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 503)
    - C, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 504)
    - D, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 505)
    - E-G, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 506)
    - H, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 507)
    - I-L, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 508)
    - M, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 509)
    - N-P, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 510)
    - R-S, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 511)
    - T-V, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 512)
    - W-Z, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 513)
    - Christmas responses, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 514, Folder 515)
    - Uncategorized, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 516)
    - Personal responses, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 517)
    - Handwritten responses, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 518)
    - Mrs. DR's responses, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 519)
  - Funeral of John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1978 July (Box 51, Folder 520)